Today's guest is
今天的來賓
the actor starring in Date My Daughter! or DMD as Soseki Tachibana,
是在《我家女兒交不到男朋友！》中 飾演橘漱石一角的
it's Yoohei Kawakami!
川上洋平先生
He's very popular. We're getting many comments.
因為收到很多觀眾詢問“他是誰？” “是去哪裡選來的？”
-"Who is he?" "Where is he from?" -Not at all.
-“好想帶他回家”等等迴響 -不敢當
-"I'd like to take him home." -No, no.
-非常有人氣
Though you're not as popular as me.
但我相信一定比不上我啦
-I believe. -Yes, of course.
那是當然的
-That's a given. -Changing topics.
-一定比不… -對了，我聽說
I hear you're actually a singer.
你本身是歌手吧
An artist?
-是音樂人啊 -是的，沒錯
It's your first time acting?
第一次演戲的感覺怎麼樣？
Yes.
因為我是第一次演戲，難免會緊張
But the cast members
但其他演員跟工作人員都對我很好
-So… -Wow, so wonderful!
-總是… -哇，好棒喔
Yes.
是
Changing topics,
對了，我聽說
you're a singer, right?
你好像是歌手
-And the group you're a part of… -Yes.
-那麼你的團體 -是
-A band, you call it?
應該說是樂團吧？ Alexander
What sort of songs do you sing?
你們都唱什麼歌呢？
-It's "Alexandros." -Oh.
樂團是叫Alexandros
With an X.
是“ros”才對
-Oh my, sorry about that. -Not a problem.
-對不起 -不會，沒關係
-I'm not caught up on the latest trends. -Not at all.
-我對年輕人的流行真的很不熟 -沒這回事
-I used to host Best Ten back in the day. -Oh.
但我以前也主持過 《The Best Ten》節目
You probably don't know.
-你應該不曉得吧？ -我知道喔
-I used to watch it with my mom a lot.
-我跟我媽媽以前常… -你知道這首歌吧？
Become the wind! Become the wind!
化為風吧，化為風吧
We become the wind, wind!
隨著風什麼的去吧
Wow, you're really bad at singing.
您…您很不會唱歌呢
You sing, then.
不然你唱啊
Can I?
可以嗎？
-Then… -You brought your guitar.
-那麼… -反正你都帶吉他來了
Excuse me for a minute.
那我獻醜了
-I'll sing it, acoustic style. -Sure.
-我唱木吉他版本的 -好
Become the wind
化為風吧
-We let the wind carry us -We become the wind, wind!
-隨著風紛飛而去吧 -隨著風什麼的去吧
-Become the wind
-化為風吧
-Become…
-化為風…
Be…
風…
Good work today. Thank you.
辛苦了，謝謝你
I became an editor
我是因為喜歡《勿忘我》
Don't Forget Me.
才成為編輯的
I joined Saneisha because I wanted to be
我是因為想成為您的責編
Aoi Minase's editor.
才會進入散英社的
Why do you say that now?
為什麼現在才告訴我？
I was going to keep it a secret.
我本來打算一輩子都不說的
Idiot.
笨蛋
What are you doing?
你們在做什麼？
What are you doing to my mom?
你要對我媽做什麼？
That was otterly weird. Get otter here!
沒事…小爪水獺
I won't say childish things like that anymore.
我不會說那種像兒童餐的話
I'm 20. I'm an adult.
我不會插嘴，我20歲了，是成人了
You've got it wrong, Sora?
不是，小空，你誤會了
How am I wrong?
我誤會什麼？
How are you wrong?
是什麼呢？
I'm sorry! I overstepped the boundary.
對不起，是我踰矩了
Something was wrong with me. I didn't mean it!
我一時忘了分寸，被氣氛影響了
You didn't mean it?
被氣氛影響？
That's my Limoncello.
而且那是我的檸檬酒
I bought it with my own part-time money.
我辛苦打工買的檸檬酒
I'll buy you more.
我會買一瓶還你
It's from Meidi-ya in Hiroo.
是廣尾明治屋的喔
Mom, this is bad! Sally!
媽媽，慘了
What if Sally finds out?
如果被她知道這件事…
You're right! This is bad!
對喔，我會被燒死，會被丟到火裡
You might be safe, Mom, but she'll burn down our house!
只有你也就算了，房子也會被燒掉
No need to worry about that.
這點你們不用擔心
Sally's been cold lately.
沙沙最近都很冷淡
She doesn't come home.
也都沒有回家
-What? -Huh?
-什麼？ -嗯？
That's enough about me.
我的事不重要
I don't know what I was thinking.
真的是我忘了分寸
I swear something like this will
我發誓絕不會再發生那樣的事
Oh, sure.
好
He swore.
居然還發誓
He swore it.
居然對我發誓了
He swore that
往後絕不會…
something like that will never happen again.
再發生那樣的事了
HIBERNATING, DO NOT DISTURB
（冬眠中 請勿打擾）
I felt like my mom was being taken away from me.
有一瞬間覺得媽媽好像會被搶走
Am I a child?
我是小孩子嗎？
You are her child.
你就是啊
It's nice to lean on your mom like that.
不過能對父母耍任性很好啊
I'm not doing that.
我才沒有耍任性
I was just surprised, that's all.
只是嚇了一跳而已
So what should we do with the title?
話說回來，你覺得要取什麼標題？
-The title, huh? -Yeah.
-標題啊 -嗯
Another World?
《Another World》？
So typical.
太普通了
Right? Your mom's so cool. She has good taste.
也是
Like her most recent series, Umbilical Cord.
像是之前連載的《命之臍帶》
So cool!
真是太帥了
It got canceled, though.
但是被腰斬了
Speaking of, what does "umbilical cord" mean?
話說《命之臍帶》是什麼意思啊？
No way! You don't know?
不會吧！你不知道嗎？
I'm a manga otaku. I don't read books.
我是漫畫宅，不看書的
Only comics. I've never read Mom's books.
只看漫畫，我沒看過我媽的小說
It means "navel string."
就是臍帶的意思
Oh, cool. That sounds deep.
好帥喔，真深奧
Hey, with Jadwiga,
對了，關於雅德維加
can we make her boobs bigger?
可以讓她再稍微，稍微一點就行了
-Just a little bit? -No.
-讓她胸部再大一點 -不要
You don't understand, Minase.
水無瀨，你可能不懂
-For men, boobs are everything. -No.
-對男人而言，胸部就是正義 -不要
We're so sorry about this.
這次的事實在很抱歉
What? Wait.
什麼？等一下，啊？
You told him what happened? You told Konishi?
你跟小西說了那件事嗎？
What do you mean?
您說的是哪件事？
I'm here to apologize about the series of events
我今天是為了 《勿忘我》電影的事來致歉
Oh, that one!
是這件事啊
I see.
原來是這樣
What else is there?
除此之外還有什麼事嗎？
No, don't worry about it.
沒有…沒什麼
We got a little too excited about
這次因為是大製作的電影
We messed up.
我們一時興奮而亂了手腳
We'll follow the original text. Naoko, the heroine, will die.
之後將按照原作 以奈緒子死亡的結局發展
They'll rewrite the whole script.
劇本也會重新寫過
We also made sure
主演的悠人也點頭答應這些條件了
Yeah. Thanks.
嗯，謝謝
This is to apologize for the mess.
這是為之前的風波賠罪
No.
不…
-Are you flustered? -No.
-您好像有點慌 -沒有
-Are you hiding something? -Nope!
-好像想隱瞞什麼
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
完…完全沒有
You said "no" eight times.
您連說了八次“完”呢
Whatever.
算了
I won't get involved in your private lives.
我不會干涉兩位的私下來往
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Why did you say that? If you won't get involved, don't say anything!
你為什麼要這麼說？ 如果不想干涉那就閉上嘴巴啊
That's why everyone hates you!
所以你才這麼討人厭啦
There's nothing going on.
我們沒有什麼論及干涉的問題
I wanted to discuss something, but I have my next appointment.
我本來想來跟您談一件事 但之後還有行程
Tachibana will talk to you about it.
那件事就請橘跟您說了
Alright.
好
I thought you brought the bean jelly from Tatsuya to apologize for the kiss.
我還以為你們是拿龍屋羊羹 來為那個吻道歉
Though we didn't kiss.
雖然最後沒親到
Should I have brought some?
我應該帶賠罪禮來比較好嗎？
Two is too much.
兩份有點太多了
Oh.
啊
This is Sora's Limoncello.
這是小空的檸檬酒
Now, everything's back to normal.
這樣一切就恢復原狀了
It's because I cried. I'm sorry.
都是因為我哭了，對不起
Konishi was going to talk about
小西總編離開前要說的
your next book, Ms. Minase.
是關於水無瀨老師新書的事
Why won't you call me Ms. Aoi?
為什麼不叫我小碧老師？
I apologize for being too friendly.
之前是我不知分寸，對不起
It was proof of me acting too friendly with you.
我覺得那是我身為責編 過於鬆懈的證據
We have to decide on what book to release next year by the end of February.
在二月底前 我們必須決定明年要出版的書
At this point, I can't write the proposal for
以我目前的狀態
Even a title will be helpful.
只有標題也沒關係 希望您能先提出來
Stop acting so professional.
不要說敬語
It feels like you're leaving me alone.
彷彿被獨自留下
It feels like you're stepping away from me.
拉開了距離
Should I come closer to you, then?
那…我應該更靠近一點嗎？
Just a bit.
剛剛好就好
The moderate distance.
在適當的距離內
Don't drink too much.
你別喝太多喔
Gon-chan, I'm stressed about work!
阿欣，我的工作真的很不妙
I need to have an idea soon, or Saneisha won't publish my next book!
再不提出作品的點子 散英社就不幫我出新書了
They set a deadline for the proposal.
還訂下企劃截稿日
It's like I'm climbing 13 steps at once!
心情很像在爬13層階梯
I thought you were writing a romance novel. No ideas yet?
你不是要寫戀愛小說嗎？ 沒有想法嗎？
I can't write romance! I got dumped again.
我寫不出戀愛故事啦，我又被甩了
Again?
又被甩啦？
Who was it this time? They all have great taste in women, huh?
這次是誰？大家都是火眼金睛啊
The heavy weight of Tatsuya's bean jellies put distance between us.
沉重的羊羹拉開了我們的距離
Same with me.
我也是
I got rejected with bean jellies from Tatsuya. Love is over.
收到以示拒絕的龍屋羊羹 結束了這段愛
When Aoba declined my arranged marriage proposal,
就是青葉小姐拒絕結婚後
the aunties brought Tatsuya bean jellies.
神林阿姨跟豐田阿姨就帶著龍屋羊羹
-We're so sorry! -What am I supposed to do with that?
-非常抱歉 ！ -什麼意思啊？
We're a taiyaki shop here!
這裡可是鯛魚燒店啊
Wait, Gon-chan, you got rejected?
什麼？你相親被退貨啦？
Rejected, huh? You poor thing!
什麼呀？原來被拒絕了，真可憐
Don't pity me! Think about it. I'm not suited for marriage.
我才不可憐 仔細想想，我這個人不適合結婚啦
I'm cooler when I'm alone. I thrive in solitude. And I'm the idol
我適合當孤獨的獨行俠 而且我可是那些以買鯛魚燒為藉口
for girls who come to see me with the pretense of buying taiyaki!
特地來見我的小姐們的偶像
-What an old idol you are! No way! -Who are you calling old?
-哇，哪來這麼老的偶像？ -我哪裡老了？
-Gon-chan. -Yeah?
-阿欣 -嗯？
-Something's been bothering me lately. -What?
-我最近很在意一件事 -喔
-You know how I shake around my head? -Yeah.
-像這樣搖頭的時候 -嗯
You've got it wrong, Sora!
不是，小空，你誤會了
-Nope! No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no -Whenever I do that.
完…完全沒有
slower than the top of my face. There's a time lag.
臉的上半部跟下半部有時間差
-My face shakes slower at the bottom! -What?
-下半部都會慢一拍才晃 -什麼？
You try too!
你也做看看
-It's shaking! -Of course!
-你也會晃 -騙人
Do you have a mirror? I want to check.
阿欣，去拿鏡子，我要確認
Here it is.
有了
Here.
來了，鏡子來了
Wait.
等等
-Maybe you shouldn't do this. -Why?
-你還是別看了吧 -什麼？
Because it's obviously a sign of aging!
你那個就是老化啊
You're getting blubbery around here. There's more fat.
你這邊都鬆弛長肉了
It means you're gaining weight.
已經發福啦
-You're right. -Yup.
-也是 -嗯
Oh.
啊
Mirror, mirror. Who's the most handsome man of all?
魔鏡啊魔鏡，世上最帥的人是誰？
It's Gon-chan, of course!
當然是阿欣呀，那還用說！
I'll poison your apple.
餵你毒蘋果喔
Gon-chan! I'm done with the delivery!
阿欣，我去外送長壽之家回來了
Good work.
辛苦了
You're here, Mom?
媽媽，你來啦
-I was drinking. -Yeah, I can tell.
-我來喝酒 -我看到了
-It's not jiggling. -It's not!
-不會晃
Shake faster. Like this.
再搖快一點
Wow. Youth is an amazing thing.
年輕人就是有本錢
What's going on?
什麼啦？
Hey, Sora. We're done today. Good work.
對了，今天可以下班了，辛苦了
Sora, you come and drink with us too. This is good.
那小空也一起來喝吧，很好喝喔
You too, Gon-chan. Heal the pain of lost love with alcohol.
阿欣也喝吧，可以撫慰失戀的心情喔
I can't get drunk today.
我今天不可以喝醉
What? Why?
為什麼？
Wait, you're dressed up today. You have plans?
這麼說你好像有打扮一番 有什麼事嗎？
Excuse me.
那個
Shunichiro called. He's almost here.
俊一郎先生剛剛打電話來 他好像快到家了
-Kenta. Can you wipe this table? -Yes!
健太，來把東西收一收
-Alright. I'm putting this away. -Wait! Why? I'm drinking this!
-我要收了 -等等
I want to clean you up too! We have
我還想把你趕走呢
an important guest.
有重要的貴客要來
An important guest?
重要的貴客？
Dad said all of a sudden,
老爸突然跟我說
he wants to introduce us to someone.
他要帶人回來，介紹給我認識
What?
什麼？
His girlfriend, right?
是他的女朋友吧
Shunichiro's girlfriend!
俊一郎叔叔的女友？
A shock, right?
嚇到了吧？
I noticed it.
我隱約有點預感
"Make me look handsome."
還說要拍帥一點
When I took the nose hair pic too.
拍鼻毛的照片時也是
It was probably for his girlfriend.
肯定是要傳給女友看
I never noticed!
我完全沒發現
You never notice. You're always only thinking about yourself…
你本來就很遲鈍，腦中只有自己
Shunichiro's a pretty handsome guy, right?
別看他那樣，他其實算是個型男
He'll probably bring a traditional Japanese beauty, like Sayuri Yoshinaga.
可能會帶像吉永小百合那樣 適合和服又端莊穩重的人回來
Right? Okay, listen.
對吧？聽好了
I can't get drunk today!
我可不能醉醺醺地見人
It's that serious?
有到這個地步嗎？
I'm not sure, but he's bringing her all the way here…
我是不清楚啦
I'm home.
我回來了
What? Everyone's here?
怎麼大家都齊聚一堂？
-Come in, Sally! -Huh?
-沙沙，快進來吧 -嗯
Hello.
大家午安
She's my lover, Saori Itoh.
我的愛人，伊藤沙織小姐
Hi.
大家好
"Sally" is that "Sally"?
你說的沙沙，就是這位沙沙嗎？
How old are you, exactly?
請…請問你幾歲？
I'm 23.
23歲
LONG LOST LOVE
（《悠久的失戀》）
PARADISE LOST - JUNICHI WATANABE
（渡邊淳一《失樂園》）
UNTIL THIS LIFE ENDS
（《直到此生結束》）
THE END OF THIS LOVE
（《這段愛情的結束》）
What is love?
戀愛到底是怎麼回事？
Don't tell him!
請你別說
What?
什麼？
Please. I need to tell him myself.
拜託，我想自己跟他說清楚
Soseki doesn't know?
漱石還不知道嗎？
Not yet.
不知道
Does Shunichiro know that you dated Soseki?
那俊一郎知道你跟漱石交往的事嗎？
He knows everything.
我全都跟他說了
Okay.
這樣啊
With these things, timing is everything.
這種事情很重時機
I stopped coming home, calling him
當對方開始覺得 “她怎麼都不回家？也都不聯絡
and tracking his phone location.
GPS也關了
Once he starts getting the hint,
會不會是那個意思？”
that's when I break it to him.
這時才是坦白的時機
If I tell him before, he'll get pissed.
如果半途就說會激怒對方
It would be dramatic!
會變成人間煉獄
Which step are you in now?
那現在到哪裡了？
Around the "the" of
“會不會是那個意思？”
"getting the hint."
大概是這個階段
People start giving up with the passing of time.
人是會隨著時間慢慢死心的
You're so experienced, Sally.
感覺你身經百戰啊
It's a big shock when you hear it from others.
若是從別人口中聽到消息 他會受到很大的打擊
Don't tell him, please!
拜託你了
I understand. I'm a romance beginner, I'll do what you say.
知道了 我這個戀愛初學者會聽你吩咐的
Good girl.
很乖…
But you loved him so much.
不過為什麼？你明明那麼喜歡他
You know,
我想得到幸福
What?
什麼？
I'm sure you know, Sora.
你也知道吧
But when I'm with Soseki, I turn into a crazy stalker.
我只要跟漱石在一起 就會變得很像跟蹤狂
I felt only pain.
總是覺得很痛苦
That's not happy love.
那樣子根本不是幸福的戀愛
But when I'm with Shunichiro,
可是，我跟俊一郎在一起時
I'm not in pain.
不會感到痛苦
I feel soft and fluffy,
感覺像睡在白雲上
like I'm sleeping on top of a cloud.
整個人輕飄飄的
But isn't love supposed to be painful?
可是戀愛不都是痛苦的嗎？
That's my guess, at least.
總覺得是這樣
What?
什麼？
In that case, Soseki will be single.
不過這麼一來，漱石就恢復單身
He could date Mom now!
可以跟我媽交往了吧
What the hell! Is that what's happening?
咦？什麼意思？有這回事嗎？
Your voice sounded a bit rough there. Don't burn our house down, okay?
你的聲音好嚇人
Oh, right.
對喔
I'll find my own happiness.
我要得到幸福
I don't care about Soseki anymore.
不要再管漱石的事了
If this love is over
已經結束的戀情
It's like it never existed
就當未曾發生過
Alright.
嗯
-Excuse me, can I get another? -Yes.
-不好意思，我要再一杯 -是
Could I?
沒關係吧？
I'll have the same.
那我也要續杯
Yes, ma'am.
好的
I'll call Mom. She'll worry.
我先跟我媽說一聲，她會擔心
You and your mom are so close.
你跟媽媽感情很好呢
It's normal, right?
很普通吧？
You don't know.
你不曉得吧
You think all mothers and daughters are like you guys.
你以為天下的母女都是這樣吧？
Am I wrong?
不是嗎？
I have a really toxic mom.
我的母親是毒親喔
She's so terrible.
真的很煩人
Maybe it's my mom's fault that I chase men
我會老是追著男人跑
all the time.
也許就是因為我媽
Ever since I was little,
從我小時候開始
Not even once.
也不曾有過被她疼愛的感覺
Really?
真的嗎？
I…
我…
I can't trust women.
無法相信女人
I don't need women in my life.
我的人生不需要女人
You should trust women.
你要學著相信
I'm sure there are women you can trust.
我認為世上也有值得相信的女人
In that case,
那…
can I trust you?
我可以相信你嗎？
Sure.
可以啊
Will you be my friend?
你願意當我的朋友嗎？
If you'll have me.
如果你不嫌棄的話
I see. You became friends?
這樣啊，你們變成朋友啦
Yeah.
嗯
-That's a great thing. -Yeah.
-這是好事 -嗯
Everyone has their issues, huh?
大家都有很多無奈呢
They do? Is that what you talked about?
是嗎？很多無奈嗎？
Issues with her family.
像是家庭問題之類的
Oh, that?
是說那種啊
We're happy.
我們家好幸福
If this love is over
已經結束的戀情
It's like it never existed
就當未曾發生過
A brooch that lost its clasp
就當作是一枚缺少針扣的胸針
I have to throw it out
只能索性丟棄
That's what she said.
歌詞是這樣
Sally was singing that.
是沙沙唱的
Love ends, huh?
戀愛終會結束啊
Yeah.
嗯
Maybe it's beautiful because it ends.
有些事物正因會結束才顯得更美好
But…
不過
Parent-and-kid relationships don't end.
親子永遠是親子
And friendships don't end.
友情也不會結束
Relationships that don't end are nice.
不會結束的關係真棒
What if you get married?
如果是結婚呢？
Then men and women don't end either.
男女的關係也不會結束吧
One in three couples get divorced.
三對夫妻裡就有一對會離婚
But we don't hear one in three children cutting off ties with their parents.
但沒聽過三個家庭中 就有一個會斷絕親子關係的說法
I see.
原來如此
We're the strongest!
還是親子最強了
Hug!
抱緊處理！
-Ouch! -A Sleeper Hold!
-痛… -接著是胴絞式固定技
I yield!
認輸…
What's wrong? Why are you this energetic?
你怎麼啦？心情太嗨了吧
I have my date tomorrow. I'm so nervous, I'll go crazy!
約會，我明天要約會 我緊張到不知所措
I'm so scared that I want to throw an uppercut!
討厭，好可怕，好想使出上勾拳！
Stop it!
別這樣
Oh, with Doctor Wataru?
跟涉師傅嗎？
A real date, without nose hair.
不裝假鼻毛的真正約會
Will you go on another date with me?
你願不願意再跟我約會一次呢？
The date you won back from him!
這是你爭取來的約會
I'm so nervous, I can't sleep!
我緊張到睡不著！
Mom, go on the date for me!
媽媽，你代替我去約會啦！
That's impossible.
那怎麼行？
I'm so pathetic!
這樣的我實在太沒用了
You're not pathetic!
才不會沒用呢！
I'm the most proud of you.
你是我最驕傲的女兒
You're the best daughter in the world!
是世界第一的寶貝女兒
Are you drunk?
幹嘛？你喝醉了嗎？
Be confident, Sora!
你要對自己有自信
When you were born, I almost gave you
你出生的時候
What is that?
那是什麼啊？
Before that, The Cutest In The World Award was mine.
在那之前的 世界第一可愛獎得主是我
Two generations of award winners!
母女都得獎嗎？
First generation!
初屆冠軍
Second generation!
第二屆冠軍
REGISTRATION CERTIFICATE
（登記證）
UMBILICAL CORD, BABY HAIR
（臍帶 胎毛）
Umbilical cord…
臍帶…
Sorry.
抱歉
I was about to leave and my client, Mr. Yoshida said his back gave out.
我正要出門時有客人來
Is he okay?
天啊，他還好嗎？
It wasn't serious. Let's go.
幸好不嚴重，走吧
Okay.
嗯
You want popcorn?
要吃爆米花嗎？
Yeah.
我要吃
Here's your order.
久等了
ISEKAI WONDER
（《異世界幻想》）
Are you okay?
-還好嗎？ -嗯
That's weird. I can't turn.
真奇怪，踩不動啊
I'm sorry!
對不起
Wow.
抱歉
Your legs are too long!
師傅的腳太長了吧
I'm too tall.
我太大隻了
I'll work hard too.
我也會努力踩的
One, two, one, two.
預備
What would you like?
想點什麼？
I'll have the ginger ale, please.
我要薑汁汽水
One ginger ale.
薑汁汽水嗎？好的
You're not eating?
你不吃點什麼嗎？
You eat. I'm not hungry.
你吃就好，我還不餓
Let's see…
那我要…
It's so fun, but I'm also so nervous that I can't eat!
快樂與緊張相繼來襲，沒有食慾
Help me, Mom!
我該怎麼辦，媽媽？
LONG LOST LOVE
（《悠久的失戀》）
Ouch!
好痛
I am alive.
我還活著
BLUE LOVE
（《藍色之戀》）
AOI MINASE IS TALENTED! BY GON
（水無瀨碧一定辦得到 沒問題 我寫得出來）
I'LL WRITE A MASTERPIECE AND GET RICH!
（我將寫出名作 席捲市場）
WRITE! DON'T GET LOST!
（別迷惘了！快寫！）
Alright.
搞定
What are you doing?
這是什麼啊？
It's a gift for you.
我送你的禮物
I haven't touched ink for a long time. Inspiring, right?
好久沒磨墨了，怎麼樣？ 很振奮人心吧？
My calligraphy's still really good.
我寫書法的功力不減啊
I wrote seven pieces, with all my heart.
七段，用心去寫的
Call me if you're coming. I'm not dressed!
來之前先打電話啦，我穿成這樣耶
Your phone was off.
你手機打不通啊
Oh, I turn it off when I'm writing.
我寫作時會關機
You're not writing.
這不是沒在寫嗎？
Don't say that!
說好不提的
"Break up? That's what you say to a geisha.
“分手，道別 那該是對仍為藝伎時的我說的
For now, tell me to die!"
對如今的我這麼說 不如叫我去死吧”
-What? -Isn't that how the quote goes?
-什麼東西？ -下面不是接這兩句嗎？
What's going on in that head of yours?
阿欣，你腦袋到底裝什麼？
What two ideas are you connecting?
神經到底是怎麼連的？
Why are you here, anyways?
是說你到底來幹嘛？
You said you couldn't write or think of any ideas. I was worried about you.
我說你啊
Where's the taiyaki? Sanmayaki is fine too.
有鯛魚燒嗎？秋刀魚燒也行
You brought snacks, right?
你有帶慰勞品吧？
You…
你啊
I brought you these!
這就是慰勞品
Ew! Where's the sugar?
哇，糖分呢？
I want sweets!
我要甜食
Lick some sugar cubes!
自己去舔砂糖啦
-I'm not a horse! -Hey.
-我是馬嗎？ -其實
I have something serious I want to talk to you about.
我是想誠懇地請教你一件事
Mom's secret technique!
媽媽的秘藏絕招
Say, "I forgot my gloves! My hands are cold!"
“我忘記帶手套了，手好冰喔”
And put your hands in their coat pocket.
一邊這麼說 一邊把手伸進對方的口袋裡
Hands…
手…
Hands?
手？
I forgot my gloves.
手套忘記拿了
Where? In that boat?
咦？忘在哪裡？
-I left them at home. -I see.
-忘在家裡了 -這樣啊
My hands are cold.
手好冰喔
I'm sure they are.
手會很冰呢
It's winter, after all.
畢竟是冬天啊
I have pockets though.
幸好有口袋
My own pockets.
我的口袋
-Sorry. -Sure.
-抱歉，我接一下 -嗯
Hello?
喂？
Why do you sound like the person you hate most called you?
你聽起來怎麼像是 接到世上最討厭的人的電話啊？
Well, you're not wrong.
實際上也相去不遠了
Should I hang up?
我還是掛掉吧
-I'm on my date. -What?
-我正在約會 -什麼？
My date!
約會
Is it going well?
還順利嗎？
Very well.
-非常順利 -這樣啊
Don't mess up.
別搞砸啦
What did you want to talk about?
是說你找我幹嘛？
I'll tell you later.
還是下次再說吧
Whatever.
算了
I thought it would be cute
幫雅德維加畫上耳朵
if we put ears on Jadwiga.
感覺會很可愛啊
I'm so bad at drawing!
唉，我果然很不會畫畫
Shunichiro's been peppy again
今天俊一郎一大早奇蒙子就很好
No one says "peppy" anymore!
現在沒人會說“奇蒙子”了啦
If I keep talking to you, I can never write anything modern!
感覺跟你聊天就更寫不出來了
He's been changing outfits since this morning.
從早上就這樣…
He went through so many.
連連換了好幾套衣服
Asking, "Which one makes me look the most handsome?"
問我穿哪套比較帥
But she was really cute.
不過那個女生真的很可愛
I totally lost to him. Even if I could marry Aoba, she's 26.
我徹底輸了，就算我跟青葉小姐結婚 她也是26歲
-Sally's 23! -23.
-但沙沙只有23歲啊 -23歲
And you didn't marry Aoba.
而且你也娶不到青葉小姐
Geez.
真是的
That doesn't matter.
不要說這件事了
I heard from Dad.
事情我都聽我爸說了
She was originally your editor's girlfriend, right?
聽說她原本是你責編的女友吧？
Yes.
對啊
-Then, she switched over to Dad. -Yup.
-但突然之間就換成我爸 -嗯
It was impressive.
完美轉換
Is she okay?
她還正常嗎？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
You know, for example… Could she be…
例如，像是…
after the money?
貪圖財產？
No, I don't think so at all.
不…應該不可能
She's not the type.
她不是那種女生
You think?
真的嗎？
You want assurance that everything will work out.
可是若問我她正不正常
-But I'm not so sure. -What?
-我沒什麼把握 -什麼？
Sally lives for love.
沙沙是為愛而生的女人
I hope Shunichiro won't get squeezed out.
俊一郎叔叔該不會被榨乾吧
Of money?
錢嗎？
Of his power to live.
生氣，活下去的力量
I didn't know that could be squeezed out.
她會榨取人的生氣嗎？
Is she a witch?
是魔性嗎？
Oh, how about this?
這樣的故事如何？
Romance between a girl in her early twenties starving for love,
一位20出頭為愛飢渴的女性
and an old man at the end of his life.
與人生步入尾聲的老人 之間的愛情故事
In the end, they end their lives together.
最後兩人在某個地方
-I'm just joking. -Geez.
-我說笑的啦，開玩笑的 -真是的
So Sora's on her date, huh?
不過
She grew up fast.
真的長大了呢
Yeah.
嗯
Aoi.
小碧
You love Sora. You should write about her for your novel.
你這麼愛小空 那寫小空的故事就好啦
That's a love story too. A story about love.
這也是愛情故事啊，是愛的故事
About Sora? How?
小空的故事嗎？要寫什麼？
She doesn't ask who the dad is?
她曾經問過她的父親是誰嗎？
Yeah.
嗯
When she does, I use my imagination.
每次她問起 我就會用我的幻想回答她
I tell her he's a super famous celebrity, or an Arab aristocrat.
她是超級名人的女兒，阿拉伯富豪
Or, I say, he wasn't Japanese!
其實她是混血兒之類的
Is that the right response as a parent?
你這母親也太奇葩了
Sora likes it too.
小空也覺得很有趣喔
You guys are weird.
真是對怪胎母女
When she was little, that Zojirushi was her dad.
是說她小時候
She doesn't ask me anymore.
她最近都不提了
She's probably no longer interested.
可能不感興趣了吧
You'll never tell her?
你打算一輩子瞞著她嗎？
I'll tell her one day.
我會說，總有一天會告訴她
Not yet. Not now.
但不是現在
Oh! I have an idea!
我想到了
What?
什麼？
I have an idea for the novel!
我想到小說的點子了
-Sorry, Gon-chan, go home. -Huh?
-抱歉，阿欣，你走吧 -咦？
-I can't work with you around. -What?
-有人在我沒辦法寫 -什麼？
Sorry. Go home.
抱歉，你回家吧
Sorry for making you walk.
抱歉讓你走這麼多路
It's fine.
不會
What should we eat tonight?
你晚餐想吃什麼？
What?
什麼？
If you go eat Italian,
去吃義大利料理的話
have tiramisu for dessert. Tiramisu and strawberries
最後一定要點提拉米蘇
Tiramisu.
提拉米蘇
Tiramisu?
咦？提拉米蘇？
Or strawberries.
或是草莓
That's dessert.
那是甜點吧
-I'm going to the restroom. -Okay.
-我去一下洗手間 -好
Let me think.
有什麼呢？
I don't know.
我沒想法
I don't think it matters.
都可以吧，想吃什麼就說啊
That won't work!
不可以這樣啦
"I don't care" is the worst answer. I read that online!
最不能說的就是都可以 網路上說會造成對方困擾
That's true.
那倒是
Hey, why are you calling me?
是說你幹嘛打給我？
Mom turns off her phone when she's writing.
我媽工作時都會關機
I'm second to Mom, huh?
我的地位緊接在媽媽後面啊？
Do you like that?
你很高興嗎？
I'm hanging up.
我要掛囉
Wait, don't! Tell me!
別掛，告訴我
Extra-large katsudon.
大碗豬排蓋飯？
That's what you want!
那是你自己想吃的吧！
Wait, that's gyudon.
那是牛丼才對
This is pretty good.
好像很不錯
This is so good!
好好喝喔
-Are you sure this is fine? -Huh?
吃這個就行了嗎？
I was planning to take you to a French restaurant or something.
本來想帶你去法式餐廳的
But that's greasy.
那種太油膩了
I love your red bean soup more than anything.
我喜歡小俊煮的紅豆湯
How nice! You two love each other. How wholesome.
真羨慕
-We went out. -Yes?
-我們今天 -是
To an aquarium together.
一起去了海生館
-Wow! -We got you a gift.
-是喔 -這是伴手禮
Really?
-要給我的嗎？ -別客氣
I'm home!
我回來了
-Welcome home! -It's getting cold.
-歡迎回家 -好像突然變冷了
Oh!
咦？
Here's your future mom!
你未來的媽媽
What?
什麼？
I'm just kidding!
我說笑的啦
Shunichiro.
俊一郎，我不介意喔
No.
不行…
Sally, you're in your early twenties!
沙沙，你才20出頭
He's a senior citizen. You're really fine with that?
這個老頭已經邁入高齡範圍了 你真的願意嗎？
Hey, Mr. Gon-chan?
你聽我說，阿欣先生
Mr. Gon-chan?
阿欣先生？
I thought Gon-chan was too friendly.
直接叫阿欣好像太沒禮貌了
Don't say that!
不會…你叫他阿欣就好啦
"Gon-chan," please.
請叫我“阿欣”
In that case, Gon-chan.
那就…阿欣
What are you smiling about?
你在暗爽什麼啊？
You know, ever since I met Shunichiro,
自從我認識俊一郎後
I can sleep.
我就能安穩入睡
I can sleep really well at night,
晚上都能睡得很熟
and the world feels warmer.
感覺世界充滿溫暖
I feel safe now.
肯定是因為我對活著這件事
I feel safe that I'm alive.
感到很安心
That you're alive? That's deep.
對活著感到安心？好像很深奧
I felt like the ground was always shaking beneath me.
我以前老是覺得自己如履薄冰 搖搖欲墜
But now, I'm alright.
可是現在不會了
I see.
這樣啊
I found an apartment,
我也租了新公寓
and I found a new job too.
也找到新的工作了
Shunichiro, you rented that apartment, right?
那是俊一郎老闆替你租的吧
You can pay me back whenever.
缺錢的話隨時跟我說喔
I'll work and pay you back.
不行，我會努力工作還錢的
I took a look.
我看完了
What do you think?
怎麼樣？
I think it's great!
我覺得很棒
I wrote it in two hours.
我寫了兩小時
That's impressive.
這個太棒了
I just wrote the main plot. I had the idea during the day.
雖然還只是粗略的大綱 是我下午突然想到的
This is about a mother and daughter, right?
這是母親與女兒的故事吧？
Right. That's the problem.
是啊，問題就在這裡
It's not a romance novel.
這不是戀愛小說
Let's pitch this.
我們去提企劃吧
What?
什麼？
I'll make sure this pitch goes through.
我一定會讓企劃通過
I want to read this novel
最重要的是
more than anyone!
我很想看這篇小說
Try it on.
你戴看看
-What? -That hat.
-什麼？ -那個
It's cute.
好可愛
Huh?
咦？
Can I buy it for you?
我買給你吧
No.
不行…
I don't need it.
不用了
32,600 YEN
（32,600日圓）
Can you wait a second?
你能等我一下嗎？
It's a designer brand. I'm going to go withdraw some money at the ATM.
這是名牌的帽子，我去領個錢
No, I don't want it.
不用了
You calling me cute, that was enough.
能聽到你稱讚我可愛就夠了
It made me happy.
我很高興
To be honest,
其實
I'm not used to going on dates with girls.
我很不習慣跟女生約會
Yeah.
嗯
So I don't know about how much money to spend. I'm sorry.
也不太懂價格，對不起
It's fine.
不會
I'm bad at rowing the swan boat too.
我連天鵝船也不會踩
I asked you to do that.
那是我說要去的
But the next spot is pretty good.
不過，待會兒要去的地方很不錯
My senpai took me there once.
我曾經跟前輩去過，雖然只是在附近
You said tiramisu and strawberries. So I chose Italian.
我聽你說想吃提拉米蘇和草莓 就猜是不是義大利料理
What a pretty restaurant. I didn't know about this place.
這家餐廳好棒
What should we get? We don't need to get a course. We can get à la carte.
你要吃什麼？
It's pretty affordable.
這裡的價格算是很親民
So don't worry…
所以你不用在意
What's wrong, Sora?
小空，你怎麼了？
My stomach hurts.
我肚子好痛
What?
什麼？
Are you okay?
還好嗎？
I'm sorry. I can walk on my own.
對不起，我可以自己走
Should we get a taxi?
要不要叫計程車？
I might get sick.
我可能會暈車
Sorry for making you drink.
對不起，是我勉強你喝酒了
It's fine.
沒事
Here.
上來吧
What?
什麼？
We're not far from TaiyouDo.
這裡到我們太葉堂並不遠
-No. -It's fine.
-不必了 -沒關係啦
I'm not tall for nothing. Come.
我的身體可不只是高大而已，來吧
This is embarrassing.
好丟臉
Not the time to be embarrassed.
現在不是說這個的時候
What are we doing at TaiyouDo?
我們去太葉堂要做什麼？
Leave it to me.
包在我身上
Right. You're a chiropractor.
對喔，你會推拿
I'm a professional.
我可是專業的喔
To tell you the truth,
其實我一直
You should've told me!
怎麼不說呢？
I was nervous for my very first date
這是我人生第一次約會
in my life.
太緊張了
You're not counting the nose hair date from the other day?
之前裝假鼻毛的那次原來不算在內啊
Sorry.
對不起
TAIYOUDO
（太葉堂 休息中）
Sorry about this.
我觸碰一下喔
I'm even more nervous now.
感覺更緊張了
Forget that it's me. Pretend I'm your mom.
你就假裝不是我，想像成你母親
Mom's patting was so fast.
我媽拍睡都拍好快
It wasn't really relaxing.
一點都不安心
What?
什麼？
If I knew this would happen,
早知如此
I would've asked you to wear the nose hair again.
就叫你裝假鼻毛來約會了
Close your eyes. Take a deep breath and relax.
閉上眼睛吧，深呼吸，放鬆身體
You're right. It doesn't hurt as much anymore.
真的呢，肚子不痛了
Right? I may not look it, but I'm pretty good.
沒騙你吧？我技術可是很好的
I know.
我知道，這條街的人
Everyone in town comes here.
大家都會來這裡
You can sleep.
你可以睡一下
Yeah.
嗯
Sorry about the Italian restaurant.
對不起，沒吃到義大利料理
Don't worry about that.
不用在意這種事
I'm sorry for not noticing that your stomach hurt.
反倒是我沒發現你肚子痛
I'm not very observant.
實在太遲鈍了
Sora, your phone is ringing.
小空，你有電話
Can you pick up, Doctor Wataru?
涉師傅，你可以幫我接嗎？
It might be my mom.
可能是我媽
Hello?
你好
Oh… What?
啊…咦？
Who is it? Sora's busy right now.
請問您是哪位？小空現在…
Oh, it's nothing! I'm sorry to bother you.
啊，我沒什麼事
TOP 20 PERFECT RESTAURANTS FOR YOUR FIRST DATE
（絕不出錯 初次約會推薦餐廳20選）
CHIROPRACTOR: TAIYOUDO
（太葉堂推拿院）
Um…
那個
With this mess, there's probably not a second date, right?
我這麼狼狽 看來沒有下一次機會了吧？
That's my line.
那是我要說的話
I put you in this mess.
害你這麼不舒服
And you'll still try with me again next time?
可以再給我一次挑戰機會嗎？
I'll bring pain killers next time!
我會記得帶胃藥的！
I won't bring my nose hair next time.
但我不會裝假鼻毛去喔
I want to bring my natural self.
我想以真正的我一決勝負
And two weeks passed after that.
到現在都過兩週了
It sounded like you two would meet the next day.
咦？還以為隔天就會再見面呢
Right? I thought that too.
對啊，沒錯吧？我也那樣覺得
But then, they had sports day at Nagaiki Home…
結果長壽之家舉辦運動會
"Nagaiki Home"?
長壽之家？
A senior care center close by.
馬路另一頭的安養中心
The old people fought hard!
老人家全都太拼命了
They wore their bodies out. So now, TaiyouDo,
搞得全身腰痠背痛，導致太葉堂
Doctor Wataru's clinic, is really popular!
涉師傅工作的那間店生意超好
He's really busy now.
他沒辦法放假
But you're texting him, right?
不過你們有在聯絡吧？
I am. I am, but…
有，有是有啦
I can't breathe if he doesn't respond.
但他一沒回覆，我就彷彿要缺氧了
Wow.
好慘
My chest gets tight just from seeing bunnies on TV.
在電視上看到兔子就會很揪心
-Bunnies? -Yeah.
-兔子？ -嗯
Oh, Doctor Nose Hair's elementary school promise!
鼻毛師傅小學時的那個約定啊
Don't call him that!
別叫他“鼻毛師傅”
Sorry.
對不起
-I want my racing heart to die! -Okay.
-好想扼殺這份激動的心情 -這樣啊
I can only sleep at night.
忙著選貼圖，只有晚上睡得著覺
So you are sleeping!
還睡得著啊！
-I don't know who I am anymore! -Oh.
有種“我是誰”的感覺
I can't tell him the truth because I don't want him to hate me.
害怕被他討厭，不敢說真心話
I haven't told him that I'm an otaku.
也不敢說我是宅女
I can feel myself shrinking.
感覺自己愈來愈渺小
Draw, Minase!
水無瀨，畫圖吧！
What?
什麼？
When you're drawing, you're free.
畫圖時的你是自由的
You won't be tied down by love.
不會受到戀愛束縛
-I'll draw! -Draw!
-我要畫！ -畫吧！
Are Jadwiga's ears like this?
雅德維加，耳朵這樣可以嗎？
-A bit bigger. -Okay.
-嗯，再大一點 -好
-Welcome! To go? -Yes.
-歡迎光臨，我要外帶 -好的
Hey. I think we should change places.
我覺得在這裡討論也差不多到極限了
Wanna come over?
那要來我家嗎？
Really?
可以嗎？
Totally fine.
我不在意啊
-Welcome! Come in, come on! -Thank you for having me.
歡迎你來
I'm so happy Sora finally started drawing manga, thanks to you!
小空終於想要畫漫畫了 都是你的功勞
It's just a hobby.
這只是興趣
Whatever you say.
好啦
You know,
不過我想在客廳閒晃
Can you work in your room? Keep the door open though.
你們去房間吧，但不可以鎖門喔
So nothing happens.
要是發生什麼事，我會很傷腦筋的
Nothing will happen.
阿姨，不會有什麼事啦
Never.
對啊
So… Irino, right?
你是叫入野嗎？
I'm Hikaru Irino.
我叫入野光
What a beautiful name. Your names mean sky and light.
是個好名字啊，你們是天空與日光呢
How bright!
好像一片晴朗的感覺
Your names glitter together!
稱呼彼此時就會閃閃發光
We don't use first names.
我們沒叫名字
We use last names, Mother.
都是叫姓氏啦
What a waste. I picked a great name for you, Sora.
真可惜，我還替你取了小空 這麼好聽的名字
Hikaru got his beautiful name from his parents too!
還有阿光父母為你取的這個名字
Oh, this is about work.
是我工作上的電話
I'll be in my writing room.
那我先回工作室了
Make yourself at home.
你們慢聊
You can drink tea here. Help yourself!
你們可以下來喝茶
I was starting to pick up on it,
雖然我是一直隱約有這個感覺
but your mom is very free-spirited.
但你媽還真是無拘無束啊
That's a nice way of putting it.
“無拘無束”只是比較好聽的說法
Really? You're sure?
咦？真的嗎？不是，你是說真的嗎？
Yeah. Midsummer Skies are Dreams.
對啊，《如夢的仲夏天空》
That's a great title!
這標題真不錯
Your proposal went through.
已經通過企劃會議了 都是靠我的力量啦
I'm so happy. I'll write this!
我很高興，我這就動筆
But why are you calling me? What about Soseki?
但為什麼是你通知我？漱石呢？
I accepted the proposal, so I call you.
企劃是我提的，當然是我通知
That's common sense, isn't it?
那是當然的啊
You're that type of person, Konishi.
你真是本性不改啊
You don't share your achievements. You ask for gratitude from others.
絕不把功勞讓給別人，親自去賣人情
Tachibana's out today. He has a cold.
橘他感冒請假了
Oh?
咦？
Blood type?
-血型嗎？ -嗯，登場人物的血型
birthdays and blood types.
要先想好出生年月日跟血型等等
Some people don't make these, but I do.
雖然有些人不會先想這些啦
Mom probably doesn't make these.
我媽感覺就不會先想好
She makes it up on the spot. She's a Blood type O.
她是隨興發揮的O型人
So Aoi Minase is Type O, huh?
原來水無瀨碧是O型啊
Yeah. I'm an outsider, so I'm Type AB.
對，而我是AB型的怪人
That makes sense.
這樣啊
I'm Type A.
我是A型
Makes sense. You're a secret hard worker.
有像喔，其實很正經的感覺
That sounds like a dig!
你真會損人
Sora! I'm going shopping!
小空，我出去買個東西
I'm getting wine to celebrate!
我去買酒回來慶祝
What are you celebrating?
要慶祝什麼？
My proposal for the new novel got accepted!
我的新小說企劃通過了
Wow, congrats!
哇，恭喜你
Will you dance the happy dance?
你跳慶祝之舞給我看
Yeah.
嗯
Congrats!
恭喜你
Congrats, congrats! Congrats, congrats!
恭喜你…
-Congrats, congrats. -Can I join?
-恭喜你… -我可以加入嗎？
-Thank you. Thank you.
-謝謝你們… -恭喜你…
Let's play a throwback song next.
接下來要播一首懷舊歌曲
Yoshiyuki Ohsawa's "So I Get Lost."
大澤譽志幸的《而我不知所措》
I DON'T BELIEVE IT AT ALL, BUT I DIAL THE NUMBER, HOPING…
（儘管我完全不相信 我還是打了那通電話…）
I want to read this novel
最重要的是，我很想看這篇小說
THANK YOU FOR EVERYTHING. GOODBYE.
（這段時間謝謝你的照顧 掰掰）
What is this?
什麼意思？
BLOOD TYPE: AB
（血型：AB型）
Huh?
咦？
I'm sure Mom doesn't make those.
我媽感覺就不會先想好
She makes it up on the spot. She's Blood type O.
她是隨興發揮的O型人
I'm an outsider, so I'm Type AB.
而我是AB型的怪人
A Type O can't have a Type AB kid, right?
O型應該生不出AB型吧？
Hello?
喂？
It's me.
是我
Did you see what I sent?
你看到我的訊息了嗎？
Yeah.
嗯
So, it's goodbye.
事情就是這樣
I wasn't enough for you?
我無法讓你安心嗎？
I'm sorry.
對不起
What will you do with your stuff?
你的東西…要怎麼辦？
Throw it out. I want everything to be new.
幫我丟掉吧，我想讓一切重新開始
Including the men.
包含男人嗎？
DIALING… AOI MINASE
（水無瀨碧來電）
WE'LL SHOW YOU BEHIND THE SCENES OF DMD!
（《我家女兒交不到男朋友！》）
-Shooting.
-準備
Start!
開拍
Oh!
啊！
Oh! I have my mask on!
我忘記摘掉口罩了
-Become the wind
-化為風吧
-Become…
-化為風…
She's not family?
他已經是無關的人了嗎？
It's weird, right?
太奇怪了
Mom's Blood type O. I'm AB.
我媽是O型，我卻是AB型
Maybe you remembered wrong.
會不會是她記錯了？
I'm going to go check.
我要去確認清楚
Don't let her test it!
別讓她做檢查
I shouldn't have done the blood test!
早知道就不去驗什麼血型了
What should I do?
怎麼辦？
Sora's leaving me. Sora's going away.
小空會消失